# MIGUEL VILÁ

miguel-vila @ github \priguelvilag@gmail.com \prighthappoond Mobile phone: 0744.8026.462

#### **PROFILE**

I am an experienced software engineer that has delivered large-scale projects. I'm keen to work with others in order to deliver quality solutions.

I have experience with a diverse set of technologies and I'm able to learn new things quickly. Although my focus is on the development side, I'm able to do things related to infrastructure and operations.

## **EDUCATION**

**Recurse Center** 

August 2016 - November 2016

New York City, United States

Self-directed, educational retreat for people who want to get better at programming

Los Andes University

January 2009 - December 2012

Bogotá, Colombia

BSc in Systems and Computing Engineering

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Disney Streaming Services**

January 2017 - Present

Software Engineer

Manchester, United Kingdom

- · Developed and maintained services related to commerce operations. Collaborated with other teams in order to deliver cross-cutting features.
- · Developed scalable backend services for user authentication. This included 4 microservices written in Scala, each one with separate responsibilities.
- · Helped to establish an environment to do end to end tests for the project. This included approximating the real infrastructure orchestrating containers.
- · Executed performance tests in those services to define sensible scaling policies.
- · Helped to establish the project's infrastructure. This included scaling groups, alarms and dashboards.
- · Took part in interviewing new candidates.

s4n

Software Engineer

January 2013 - June 2016 Bogotá, Colombia

- · Developed enterprise software for insurance companies. Used a variety of technologies: Java, Scala, JavaScript amongst others.
- · Worked remotely for a company in the United States developing a REST API using Scala.
- · I was the technical leader of a small team of engineers. Guided technical decisions and helped members new to the tech stack or to the team become productive.

#### Los Andes University

August 2011 - May 2012

Teaching Assistant for Design and analysis of algorithms.

Bogotá, Colombia

· I evaluated student homework and exams. Gave some classes in preparation for exams.

## CIACUA, Los Andes University

Software Engineer

March 2011 - August 2011 Bogotá, Colombia

· I worked in the software reingeneering process of an application used for the design and simulation of distributed water networks. I documented the design in UML and fixed bugs found in a version update.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages

(in order of skill): Scala, Java, Javascript.

Infrastructure: Mostly AWS. Cloudformation, ECS, CloudWatch, DynamoDB.

Versioning Systems: Git, SVN.